[{"id": "5b32337bbf195a31e15d739b", "question": "Botswana is landlocked by which four countries?", "answer": "South Africa, Namibia, Zimbabwe, and Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5921fccea4edfd43a087adc1", "question": "What number is represented by \"L\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "50", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what platoon was Abe Simpson in charge of during WWII?", "answer": "The Flying Hellfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf96", "question": "What is the fear of tapeworms known as?", "answer": "Taeniophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a558", "question": "What is the capital of Washington?", "answer": "Olympia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc0", "question": "The USS Kearsarge is best known for sinking what Confederate vessel?", "answer": "CSS Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8b", "question": "Which of the nine Muses was the goddess of dancing?", "answer": "Terpsichore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddd1c6ce05a3942286da0", "question": "Heisenberg is the nickname of the main character in which popular television series?", "answer": "Breaking Bad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c448", "question": "How many chromosomes does a wolf have?", "answer": "78", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb6", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Manchester England\"?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5952413d736d4be723796b61", "question": "Which superhero was created by Mike Young, as a way to help his child sleep at night?", "answer": "SuperTed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b082", "question": "What famous woman became known as \"The Lady with the Lamp\" during the Crimean War?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f3f7caf848b908361b86c", "question": "What do the numbers on a roulette wheel add up to?", "answer": "666", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3c0e44f0f6af5b06662b", "question": "A \"peck\" is how many imperial quarts?", "answer": "8", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e1", "question": "What color is the bottom strip of Egypt's flag?", "answer": "Black", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590498eecf93664eb104868c", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Oklahoma?", "answer": "Oklahoma City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c3508815febcc896f9258", "question": "In which country would you find the motor racing circuit called Kyalami?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c902fbde8045e48466e6", "question": "Which farm animal sleeps standing up?", "answer": "Horses are the only farm animal that can sleep standing up, and it's due to the unique way their legs are structured.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb30", "question": "What is your occupation if you are sometimes referred to as an apiarist?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeef", "question": "Who commanded the English Fleet against the Spanish Armada in 1588?", "answer": "Admiral Charles Howard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe77014eec85e375820b2f4", "question": "Which body of water is the Nile River\u2019s primary reservoir?", "answer": "Lake Victoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab9", "question": "Sauerbraten is a specialty beef dish that originated in what country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62b", "question": "What river flows along the southern border of South Carolina?", "answer": "Savannah River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d98", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Joad?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a868", "question": "Which countries share land borders with Spain?", "answer": "France, Portugal and Andorra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea9", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Clayton, Katy and Nick?", "answer": "Adam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ff", "question": "What US vice president referred to his critics as \"nattering nabobs of negativism\"?", "answer": "Spiro Agnew", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febba487e83c707845b2144", "question": "The Philadelphia Flyers of the 1970's were known as the \"Broad Street\" what?", "answer": "Bullies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee6", "question": "Who preceded Georges Pompidou as French President?", "answer": "Charles de Gaulle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f46bcee580c7f8fd1e58", "question": "What is the state animal for Florida?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25f1876682715b82711ce1", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4041ff048f679a45ab67", "question": "What is an urolith?", "answer": "A bladder stone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd3b97e83c707845b2154", "question": "How many noble houses of Westeros are there in \"Game of Thrones\"?", "answer": "Nine (Arryn, Baratheon, Greyjoy, Lannister, Martell, Stark, Targaryen, Tully and Tyrell)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08f", "question": "Who recorded the albums \"Cuts Both Ways\", and \"Into The Light\"?", "answer": "Gloria Estefan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984c", "question": "The artist Richard David James is better known by what stage name?", "answer": "Aphex Twin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012195a63c99d48cd169af8", "question": "How many bricks were used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "10 million", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c082", "question": "What is the practice of creating decorative shapes by trimming trees and shrubs?", "answer": "Topiary", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd7", "question": "Which US vice president shot a Texas attorney while out hunting quail in 2006?", "answer": "Dick Cheney", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab96a986faa38a764be521", "question": "Despite not being the first company to make a minivan, which company introduced the first successful mass-produced minivan in 1983?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4a3949076251badbeab1", "question": "In which Texas city will you find the famous Alamo?", "answer": "San Antonio -- The old mission was the site of a doomed battle in Texas\u2019s war for independence from Mexico.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7f", "question": "What comedian voiced Mr. Potato Head in the \"Toy Story\" movies?", "answer": "Don Rickles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fb", "question": "Where is the opening scene of the movie \"Love Actually\" shot?", "answer": "An airport", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ca", "question": "What comedian is remembered for his saying \"Everybody wants ta get inta de act\"?", "answer": "Jimmy Durante", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d4", "question": "Who ordered the disastrous \"Great Leap Forward\" in 1958?", "answer": "Mao Tse-tung", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a1e1cc7b5a031299b745735", "question": "Which brothers published the storybook entitled \"Children's and Household Tales\" in the 19th century?", "answer": "The brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f0", "question": "Which artist painted \"American Gothic\"?", "answer": "Grant Wood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66d94a5bfecdd737e08a3", "question": "What was the most popular month for weddings in the U.S. in 2019?", "answer": "October", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f5d35cb9e8bda682136b", "question": "Samuel Miller patented the first steam-powered what in 1806?", "answer": "Drill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59da1af6f6756c9b30ba14f4", "question": "In which film did a Rolls Royce have the number plate AU1?", "answer": "Goldfinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1d", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb2087e83c707845b2110", "question": "A group of lizards is called what?", "answer": "A lounge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55c", "question": "What city is nicknamed the \"Big Apple\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9dc", "question": "What is a group of whales commonly called?", "answer": "Pod", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d48f2596a59cbdfbd3a5", "question": "What is the main substance found in bones?", "answer": "Collagen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339264", "question": "What three letter name did the band formerly known as \"Slut Bank and Twisted Kites\" finally settle on?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e008fe83fe1f2a824b85", "question": "What did Evangelista Torricelli invent?", "answer": "Mercury barometer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c353", "question": "Mn is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Manganese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff14036b0ee8c595b6d3997", "question": "The Last Supper mural originally included which body part of Christ that has since been removed?", "answer": "Feet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b089", "question": "When was the Hubble telescope launched into orbit?", "answer": "April 24, 1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fc", "question": "Which country were the 2016 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f3", "question": "In The Simpsons, who do Jumbo and Kearney usually hang around with?", "answer": "Dolph", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea41d8ff048f679a45ab72", "question": "Which breed did the English call a coach dog", "answer": "Dalmatian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada1", "question": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh was better known as who?", "answer": "Sundance Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a9", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Japan?", "answer": "Fuji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f6", "question": "What sport do Fuzzy Zoeller and Kermit Zarley play?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3dd044f0f6af5b066640", "question": "Andorra la Vella is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Andorra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27a", "question": "What is the syrup drained from raw sugar?", "answer": "Molasses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b906364247bf200fb886", "question": "Aulophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Flutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015de62fe83fe1f2a824b69", "question": "What Spartan king led a small army of 300 Spartans against a vastly superior Persian force in the Battle of Thermopylae?", "answer": "Leonidas, King of Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d076e3870e6f05ba60085f", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", what is the shrew's last name?", "answer": "Minola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c47", "question": "What ventriloquist was best known for his dummy Charlie McCarthy?", "answer": "Edgar Bergen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca42", "question": "Which vital organ does the adjective renal refer to?\u00a0", "answer": "Kidney\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9ba81364247bf200fb898", "question": "Which political party was co-founded in West Germany in 1979 by the late Petra Kelly?", "answer": "The Green Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7714ff048f679a45abc6", "question": "Which volcano erupted from January 18-21, 1951, causing over 3,000 deaths?", "answer": "Mt. Lamington, Papua New Guinea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81d44d0de9af39e9d468d", "question": "What was the original name for Africa?", "answer": "Alkebulan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a20512f2a7826b9b8717", "question": "What 1980's cartoon was a showcase for \"New Wave\" Music videos?", "answer": "Kidd Video", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac48", "question": "What was the series of campaigns to wrest the Holy Land from Muslim Turks called?", "answer": "The Crusades", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66de0a5bfecdd737e08a8", "question": "What classic book inspired the name of Starbucks?", "answer": "Moby Dick", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078a310eee65b76b9f265f", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f24eff048f679a45aab8", "question": "What type of cloud is often described as \"cotton-like\"?", "answer": "Cumulus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58bb34e9e368446ca7bd684c", "question": "What widely consumed drug acts as a natural defence to protect the seeds of the coffee plant?", "answer": "Caffeine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bc", "question": "What nationality was Roald Dahl?", "answer": "Welsh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339317", "question": "In the film \"Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl\", the way Johnny Depp portrays Jack Sparrow was inspired by whom?", "answer": "Keith Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b746", "question": "The serial killer Larry Eyler was also known as what?", "answer": "The Highway Killer/The Interstate Killer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e96f97ccba3ffe45786f5", "question": "A 1 to 3 mph wind on the Beaufort scale is called what?", "answer": "Light air", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c7fa877e98cb977789da", "question": "In which capital city would you find the Marley Museum?", "answer": "Kingston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "595641ae803c1f1ebcc4a02a", "question": "The ball on top of a flag pole is called a what?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3856ff048f679a45ab23", "question": "Who is considered the \"father\" of organic chemistry?", "answer": "Friedrich W\u00f6hler", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0c", "question": "Homichlophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3a", "question": "How long is the Le Mans endurance motor race?", "answer": "24 hours", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ae", "question": "Whose movie character's full name is Charles Lee Ray?", "answer": "Chucky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b5c2e662d71a53650ffe", "question": "Which literary hero famously goes to battle against windmills?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb5", "question": "What are the \"spots\" in the British dessert Spotted Dick?", "answer": "Currants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5f", "question": "Who patented the first practical fountain pen back in 1884?", "answer": "Lewis Waterman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c753fbde8045e48466c1", "question": "What is the scientific name of the plant used to make liquorice?", "answer": "Glycyrrhiza glabra, the plant used to make liquorice, is native to Europe and Asia.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b372dc1c3f17ccc40c8e28", "question": "Rodney Dangerfield, Phil LaMarr and Randy Quaid starred in which 2005 film?", "answer": "Back by Midnight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80709de59ea584496feb6", "question": "In which continent would you find the river Nile?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ce", "question": "What TV spy often tried to pass himself off as a salesman for the Pontiac Greeting Card Company?", "answer": "Maxwell Smart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f8", "question": "What explorer disappeared in 1928 while on a rescue mission for survivors of the crashed airship \"Italia\"?", "answer": "Roald Amundsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121c6763c99d48cd169b17", "question": "Who was the designer of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "French sculptor Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Auguste Bartholdi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb3", "question": "What airport has the code MME?", "answer": "Durham Tees Valley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a00", "question": "What 1981 thriller opens with the discovery of three faceless corpses at an amusement park in Russia?", "answer": "Gorky Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc09", "question": "What high civilian Indian award was Mother Teresa awarded?", "answer": "Bharat Ratna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b924", "question": "What publication makes weather predictions based on a secret formula developed in 1792?", "answer": "The Old Farmer's Almanac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393af", "question": "What year did the first Cannes Film Festival take place in?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c0", "question": "What kind of gun did Han Solo use in the Star Wars films?", "answer": "Mauser C96", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab60", "question": "Prague is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008c40cf842fa4c4ba969e", "question": "With which horror film series would you associate the character Leatherface?", "answer": "Texas Chainsaw Massacre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba66", "question": "What branch of the U.S. military features the Blue Angels precision flying squad?", "answer": "US Navy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a734", "question": "The Battle of Gettysburg occurred in which US state?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a567", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Sooner State\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93dc86bd93ce3a4e5f6b9", "question": "How long is one Pluto year?", "answer": "248 Earth years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339121", "question": "Who wrote the 1895 book \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97f", "question": "What is the official residence of the president of France?", "answer": "Elysee Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e2", "question": "In sports, what does IIHF stand for?", "answer": "International Ice Hockey Federation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a348", "question": "What song contains the lyric \"If you've had a dose of a freaky ghost?\"", "answer": "The Ghostbusters theme song", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4edc106d333868d34d770", "question": "What do you call the moveable indicator on a Ouija board which is shaped like a heart?", "answer": "Planchette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339906", "question": "What elderly TV detective came out of retirement after his son, Hal, was killed?", "answer": "Barnaby Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc46", "question": "What year did professional tennis player, Andre Agassi, retire from tennis in?", "answer": "2006", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b91", "question": "According to their own theme song, what 1960's group was \"too busy singin' to put anybody down\"?", "answer": "The Monkees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590683dfff9c0647b50a80ab", "question": "Which album won the 2016 Grammy Award for \"Album of the Year\"?", "answer": "1989", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339150", "question": "Who owned a chimp called Chee-Chee?", "answer": "Doctor Dolittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba46", "question": "What Philadelphia building appears on the back of the US $100 bill?", "answer": "Independence Hall", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa38c9c73aa70ea0b70ad5", "question": "Basundi is a dairy product that is popular in which part of the world?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cf", "question": "What kind of stone is the Taj Mahal made of?", "answer": "Marble", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d9", "question": "What was the capital city of West Germany from 1949 to 1990?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c8", "question": "Who owned the detective agency in the TV show \"Remington Steele\"?", "answer": "Laura Holt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67a", "question": "How many bends does a standard paperclip have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338890", "question": "What is Bruce Wayne's heroic identity?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36d1d0ada16518afdc040", "question": "Who founded Pepperidge Farm?", "answer": "Margaret Rudkin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3eac538e4e5d4832e6315", "question": "On which day of Creation did God make the land and seas?", "answer": "Third", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c5920775fa611bce67c9", "question": "What spice gives cheddar cheese its trademark orange hue?", "answer": "Annatto -- Cheddar cheese is actually white.  The spice comes from the pulverized seeds of the South American achiote tree.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a0", "question": "Which fashion designer was shot dead in the summer of 1997?", "answer": "Gianni Versace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae94aa574a5ce6b56b824a", "question": "What was the full name of Dr. Henry Jekyll's alter ego?", "answer": "Edward Hyde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34c", "question": "What is the world's widest river?", "answer": "The Amazon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac60", "question": "Which carved stone was the key to the understanding of Egyptian hieroglyphics?", "answer": "The Rosetta Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1e", "question": "What key is to the right of T on a standard keyboard?", "answer": "Y", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b3", "question": "What is the main ingredient of guacamole?", "answer": "Avocados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c511", "question": "What are deheaded, deveined and sorted by size in a Laitram machine?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b221", "question": "What city was Rasputin killed in?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1de", "question": "Which US president lived in Mount Vernon?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7ce47877e98cb97778a3f", "question": "What are the 3 major islands of the Philippines?", "answer": "Luzon, Visayas and Mindanao", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cce", "question": "Stephen Crane's \"The Red Badge of Courage\" is set during which war?", "answer": "US Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab9b", "question": "The port of Piraeus is located in which European country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912d", "question": "Dale Arden is a character from which classic American comic strip?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb05", "question": "What year was the Pioneer 10 space probe launched into space?", "answer": "1972", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b904", "question": "What board game introduced the world to the wonders of pop-o-matic dice?", "answer": "Trouble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc0", "question": "David Bowie is known for his distinct voice type?", "answer": "Baritone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc2", "question": "Whom did Vietnam gain independence from in 1954?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb7", "question": "In The Green Lantern comic book series, what is the color used to represent will power?", "answer": "Green", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40e", "question": "What year did Bangladesh become independent from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600240884be4723ccac22166", "question": "In the film \"The Hunt for Red October,\" Captain Marko Ramius is from what country?", "answer": "Lithuania", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c73", "question": "What Shakespearean character has the most lines?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d1178b4fea7fe947a2227a", "question": "What is the name for the study of fluids?", "answer": "Hydraulics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c279", "question": "What is December's birthstone?", "answer": "Turquoise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600240d14be4723ccac22169", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dances with Wolves\"?", "answer": "Michael Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea1", "question": "What city's Hotel Adlon was the site of Michael Jackson's 2002 baby dangling?", "answer": "Berlin's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69f9120565ad31a57c78d", "question": "What sport\u2019s first non-military competition was hosted in Norway in 1868?", "answer": "Downhill skiing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b43", "question": "Taking advantage of a fad at the time, what song became a #1 hit for Ray Stevens in 1974?", "answer": "The Streak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e8", "question": "What year were X-rays discovered?", "answer": "1895", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3d3dff048f679a45ab49", "question": "Where is the observatory where Percival Lowell first theorized the existence of Pluto?", "answer": "Flagstaff, Arizona", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec87b6ec223966ae8f8817", "question": "The theme song to the 1990's Fox Network television sitcom \"Get a Life\" was performed by which band?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4032ff048f679a45ab66", "question": "To which part of physics does the Archimedes' Principle refer?", "answer": "Buoyancy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e1a9fcbed638185eaa1c", "question": "Which country is connected to the most countries by land?", "answer": "China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a716", "question": "Lake of the Ozarks is located in which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6c", "question": "Who played the role of TV's J. J. Starbuck?", "answer": "Dale Robertson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec9", "question": "What kind of blood is dumped on Stephen King's \"Carrie\"?", "answer": "Pig's blood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ec", "question": "What fish became popular at fish stores after the release of \"Finding Nemo\"?", "answer": "Clown fish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a977", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Rajya Sabha?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7e7a4b24f84e0b9f9ffbb", "question": "Which is the largest state in Australia\u00a0by land area?", "answer": "Western Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9bb", "question": "What is the name of an eagle's nest?", "answer": "An Eyrie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7dabff048f679a45abfb", "question": "Algophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Pain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590720463745b36be73039f0", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the eighth day?", "answer": "8 Maids a-Milking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f716ea9e54d890926f6e0", "question": "In which country is the Troi-Rivieres bridge?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c9b6877e98cb977789fb", "question": "Jamaica is considered part of which continent?", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc0", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Paula Abdul?", "answer": "Rush Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae94f4574a5ce6b56b824d", "question": "Which African country is Lilongwe the capital of?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ef", "question": "How many US States end with the letter N?", "answer": "4", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11d", "question": "What Monty Python movie was banned in Norway?", "answer": "Life of Brian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949c", "question": "What game was the game show \"Pantomime Quiz\" based on?", "answer": "Charades", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ae", "question": "How many sides does a rhombus have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a365", "question": "What country did the Venetian blinds originate in?", "answer": "Persia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca03", "question": "What natural events are ranked in severity by the Saffir Simpson scale?", "answer": "Hurricanes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb7587e83c707845b212f", "question": "What were comets called in ancient Greece?", "answer": "Hairy stars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a994761d1b4d384d5d698", "question": "Who played the role of Quint Asper in the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa5ad73838c5c8a417f29", "question": "What do speleologists study?", "answer": "Wild cave systems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a367", "question": "What US city had the first subway?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338893", "question": "What is heaven to fallen Norse warriors?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998a", "question": "What rocker was backed by a band called \"Crazy Horse\"?", "answer": "Neil Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d0442596a59cbdfbd379", "question": "Who said, \"When I do good, I feel good. When I do bad, I feel bad. That's my religion\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad72", "question": "What US Navy intelligence vessel was attacked by North Korea on January 23, 1968?", "answer": "USS Pueblo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92d", "question": "Where is the Swimming Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Fort Lauderdale, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd69f486c0f9723ab15cb29", "question": "Who was the first woman to win the Pulitzer Prize?", "answer": "Edith Wharton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c5", "question": "What desert is home to the Ahaggar and Tibesti mountains?", "answer": "Sahara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c77", "question": "What year was Indiana Jones first introduced to the public?", "answer": "1981", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071bc23745b36be73039c4", "question": "What is the only food that cannot give Tony Chu a psychic sensation in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "Beets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067fe7ff9c0647b50a8088", "question": "What was the last book novelist Harper Lee published before passing away in February of 2016?", "answer": "Go Set a Watchman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393cc", "question": "In which James Bond movie does the character Pussy Galore appear in?", "answer": "Goldfinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbf", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Water Buffaloes\" fraternity?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007815fbd51d85e222ab64b", "question": "What art movement employs aspects of mass culture, such as advertising, comic books and mundane cultural objects?", "answer": "Seeking to elevate popular culture to the level of fine art,\u00a0Pop artists\u00a0celebrated commonplace objects and everyday people.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b343", "question": "Who was UK Labour cabinet minister and social reformer Frank Pakenham better known as?", "answer": "Lord Longford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab10", "question": "Which sea lies west of mainland Greece?", "answer": "Ionian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964b", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1995 movie \"Babe\"?", "answer": "Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb9c67e83c707845b213f", "question": "What do you call someone who studies sea shells?", "answer": "Conchologist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb1", "question": "Over what part of Captain Robert Jenkins were Britain and Spain at war in 1739?", "answer": "His ear", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a82", "question": "What female dog is the secret object of Underdog\u2019s affection?", "answer": "Sweet Polly Purebred", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25ca1b63e5727cf5a4861", "question": "In which city was Tupac Shakur shot dead?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e94cc7ccba3ffe45786d7", "question": "What year did the programming language \"COBOL\" first appear, before being standardized in 1968?", "answer": "1959", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8abf201dd7bf43be5e768", "question": "Most of a US penny is made from what type of metal?", "answer": "Zinc", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2f", "question": "Who was the first U.S. billionaire?", "answer": "John D. Rockerfeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc19", "question": "What company introduced Spam to the market in 1937?", "answer": "Hormel Foods Corporation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939c", "question": "Who plays the role of Captain John Miller in the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\"?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda9", "question": "What two people appear in the famous photo taken aboard the yacht Monkey Business in May 1987?", "answer": "Gary Hart and Donna Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4a4fc6c6b019850c9a73", "question": "What did the first vending machine dispense?", "answer": "Holy Water", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a956", "question": "Which European country replaced the Deutsche mark with the Euro?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c6", "question": "What is considered the sister language of English?", "answer": "German", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc7", "question": "According to Clarence in \"It's a Wonderful Life\", what happens every time a bell rings?", "answer": "An angel gets its wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd86877e98cb97778a38", "question": "Which US state hosts the world lumberjack championship?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a47d20565ad31a57c7bd", "question": "Who was the first U.S. President born west of the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc4616de0eb824d4052f2", "question": "\"Jana Gana Mana\" is the national anthem of which Asian country?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febafef7e83c707845b2101", "question": "What was the first live-stream video on the internet?", "answer": "A garage band performance", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c8", "question": "Bismarck is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd54", "question": "The Obie Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Off-Broadway theater", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5fc", "question": "Which is the smallest planet in our Solar System?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbd4c4000d154d7af00b8d0", "question": "Sir Mix-a-Lot's song \"Baby Got Back\" is also known by what other name?", "answer": "I Like Big Butts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dc0ae748bb36357acddb", "question": "What is the name of the ship Darwin sailed on when he made his historic visit to the Gal\u00e1pagos Islands?", "answer": "H.M.S Beagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d2", "question": "The fruit \"laraha\" is a relative to what better-known fruit?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9d", "question": "What movie did the villain Alonzo Harris appear in?", "answer": "Training Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a258", "question": "At what age did Alfred Hitchcock die?", "answer": "80", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e6", "question": "What Jules Verne adventurer fired his valet for bringing him shaving water two degrees below his requirement?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fc", "question": "The \"Oort Cloud\" is made up of what?", "answer": "Comets", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf4", "question": "Whose painting entitled \"Impression: Sunrise\" gave the name to the Impressionist movement?", "answer": "Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e940c7ccba3ffe45786cd", "question": "What year did Buddy Holly die in a plane crash?", "answer": "1959", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec23158dc25ca9e12ef62d", "question": "Who did Jersey Joe Walcott defeat at age 37 to win the heavyweight title?", "answer": "Ezzard Charles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339614", "question": "What breed of dog is Scooby-Doo?", "answer": "Great Dane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d57", "question": "Under which pseudonym did J. K. Rowling publish \"The Cuckoo's Calling\" in 2013?", "answer": "Robert Galbraith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb8", "question": "Which Andrew Lloyd Webber musical is set in the \"Troubles Of Belfast\"?", "answer": "The Beautiful Game", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b8", "question": "What musical instrument does Sherlock Holmes play for relaxation?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a613", "question": "Name the largest landlocked country in Europe?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb50", "question": "What does the abbreviation ROI stand for in the financial world?", "answer": "Return on Investment", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9a", "question": "The Art Nouveau designer Rene Lalique worked with what material?", "answer": "Glass", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523c45736d4be723796b36", "question": "What is the name of the highway that travels through all ten Canadian provinces?", "answer": "Trans-Canada Highway, or Route Transcanadienne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe258b0658e585fda9cfa40", "question": "What type of sugar typically includes a small amount of cornstarch to prevent lumping while mixing?", "answer": "Powdered sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d95", "question": "What TV character had great success with his recipe for Chocolate Salty Balls?", "answer": "Chef", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd969c023c87fd04dd15e0c", "question": "What was the first major battle fought only in the air?", "answer": "Battle of Britain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c673", "question": "Jonas Salk discovered a vaccine for what disease?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b301", "question": "In what city is the Schloss Cecilienhof, site of a historic 1945 conference?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d2db2596a59cbdfbd394", "question": "The Iguazu Falls lie on the border of Brazil and which country?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43a", "question": "When was Albert Einstein born?", "answer": "1879", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1b", "question": "Filbert is an alternative name for which nut?", "answer": "Hazelnut", "category": "science"}]